Well, Sigmar, welcome to
the Junkyard Love podcast,
man. Thank you one more time
for your time. I appreciate you.
00:00:15:15 - 00:00:17:11
Speaker 2
Jacob. Thank you for having me.
00:00:17:13 - 00:00:36:00
Speaker 1
Yeah. I'm looking forward to a man. Like
I was just telling you, I've. I've really,
loved exploring your journey, exploring what
you're all about. There's a lot of fascinating
stuff. Anybody listening? Right off the bat,
look down in the description. All of his links
are there. You can check out Love Tune or more,
but starting us off here, Sigmar, if someone
has clicked on this because it looks kind of
curious, they don't know anything about you.
00:00:36:00 - 00:00:42:04
Speaker 1
They've never heard of you. Here's
the most impossible question for
you. Who are you and what is it that you do?
00:00:42:06 - 00:01:03:21
Speaker 2
So I'm the founder of of love Tuna and
love tuna. This little device here,
it's a meditation device, so it's basically a
combination of, sound healing and breathwork. So
you take a conscious breathing break, you arrive
in the here and now, and on the spiritual level,
you invite the frequency of love or
the power of love into your life.
00:01:03:21 - 00:01:29:22
Speaker 2
So. And why? The power of love is because
it's calibrated to 520 territories,
is there's no tuner here that vibrates on
520Hz. What is understood the miracle tone
or the love frequency, the DNA repair. So
what you basically do you blow through this
little whistle makes this tone. This
frequency connects into your body,
physically aligns you water molecules,
gives you the feeling of relaxation.
00:01:29:22 - 00:01:39:16
Speaker 2
You do a profound breathing cycle.
Yeah. And that's already half of
off the rant if you want to call it. And
then it's also a shortcut to meditation.
00:01:39:18 - 00:01:51:13
Speaker 1
Yeah. Oh man. There's a lot of
exciting doors to open there. Okay,
so before we get into more details about the
actual Love Tuner, how did you specifically
stumble upon this? Like why would this be
an interesting thing for you to create?
00:01:51:15 - 00:02:16:10
Speaker 2
I, I relocated, from Europe, like a little bit
not 20 years ago of to to the United States. I
was in New York before, and 20 years ago
I moved to California and I started right
then actually meditating. And it became a
important part of my life. It helped me,
you know, regulate stress. And I was always out
see poets and, you know, but I was super busy.
00:02:16:10 - 00:02:43:13
Speaker 2
I was in fashion. I was in design. And that's
my background as an architect as well. And,
and my main outlet was always nature,
you know, like whatever surfing, running,
hiking, whatever you do. And obviously you
breathe a lot when you swim and in all those
activities and sometimes this stuff was not
enough anymore. And this is when, you know,
I started meditating and it was something that
really helped me, that grounded me in the morning.
00:02:43:13 - 00:03:07:10
Speaker 2
I did it very rigidly every morning. Every
night. And so about a couple of years into
this meditation journey, I got turned on to
the frequency of 528Hz, and I have no clue.
Like most of you, your listeners probably don't
know. No, I mean, now we are 20 years later,
so a lot of people know about it, but, I
had no clue what the 528Hz frequency is.
00:03:07:12 - 00:03:30:16
Speaker 2
We did a guided, press work, meditation, and the
person brought in speakers, and it was not from
YouTube. It was not from a device. He literally
had speakers, and he had the original tone. And he
guided us through a meditation that took about
an hour long. He called it the Aqua Journey,
and he helped us with breathwork and
this sound to go into a meditative state.
00:03:30:18 - 00:03:57:10
Speaker 2
And it was my experience. It was the most profound
one, and literally something where I went like,
wow, this was the most profound meditation
ever had. It was the most profound,
experience I had and the most connection
ever felt to my own heart. And like,
really getting out of your head, into your heart
and have this overall, understanding about what
actually the universe is and what the cosmos
is, that everything is one and one and all.
00:03:57:15 - 00:04:23:16
Speaker 2
So little did I know that this becomes my own
journey. So, the person that introduced me to this
breathwork facilitator was an old friend of mine
that was back then, really working on the idea of
creating, a meditation device with knowledge. The
love tiona. And, and we have been communicating
for a couple of months, and at one point I said
the Muslim come to California, let's sit down.
00:04:23:18 - 00:04:56:13
Speaker 2
Let's make this this product. And I was, you know,
I was a fashion designer, was a, an architect,
too. It was easy for me to make a product. And
then. Yeah, a couple of months later, we had this
product in our hand, and we started this journey.
And the whole thing was. And this is why we have
on all our devices, we have a slogan on this
called One Journey because it was literally, it's
the one journey that we all on and and laughed,
you know, was never I mean, now it's a commercial
company, you know, it's a e-commerce company
and we're selling on the internet and whatnot.
00:04:56:15 - 00:05:17:15
Speaker 2
But, it started as a love and
peace mission because we literally
we actually found that this is the most profound
connection to our heart. So this frequency
triggers something in you that makes you we
lead, we talk about have coherent, you know, when
you're coherent with your thoughts and with your
heart. But this event takes it to the next level.
00:05:17:15 - 00:05:40:16
Speaker 2
It takes it out of your head, into your heart. So
you really feel what we're actually our feelings
are coming from or should be coming from, you
know, where we actually should live our life,
you know, and this is heart based and, and, on a,
on a heart level, humanity is totally connected.
You know, there's no there's no disconnect,
you know, so hearts are always curious.
00:05:40:18 - 00:06:03:14
Speaker 2
The energy of hearts is about 55,000 times
more, strong at a magnetic field than the
magnetic field of the brain, for example. And
still we only, you know, believe what the brain
just tells us. But if we are heart focused and
we live on this level, and what our hearts are
doing is basically they're curious, they
want to connect to another heart energy.
00:06:03:16 - 00:06:32:17
Speaker 2
And what literally separates us is our intellect.
So if we would just live on this heart level,
we could be really like, whatever. But the
hippie movement was all love and peace and
no more war. But I mean, I'm not a hippie,
but I'm a very big believer in this concept,
and I think if we would all focus
on this and really go on our heart
level and make heartfelt decisions,
I think we could overcome separation.
00:06:32:19 - 00:06:44:12
Speaker 2
And, and unify humanity. So this is how last time
I came around, it was a love and peace mission.
It still is a love and peace mission. It's
literally about literally about unifying hearts.
00:06:44:14 - 00:07:03:17
Speaker 1
Yeah. Wow. So incredible, man. I was
thinking about you were talking about
kind of our intellect, you know, sort
of versus our heart, as if they're kind
of like two different places for us to, to
live from or act from, in a way. I myself,
I'm into meditation. And so, you know, these
are not super unusual things for me to hear.
00:07:03:19 - 00:07:20:24
Speaker 1
I can do guided meditations where I can
kind of actively drop into my heart from
my head. And you can kind of notice these very
subtle little things. But I do think about,
you know, me, seven, eight years ago
before I really got into meditation,
I'm not sure what I would be hearing when
I'm here in a conversation like this.
00:07:21:04 - 00:07:32:21
Speaker 1
So I wonder, Sigma, I feel like you'd be
able to explain this pretty well. Can you
explain a little bit more about this? Like
what's the difference between living in your
intellect kind of in your head versus living
in your heart? And what does that feel like?
00:07:32:23 - 00:07:56:10
Speaker 2
I mean, we we are firing about 75,000
SAR today, and if we don't start,
like having kind of a soft hygiene, like a
spiritual hygiene to stop this thought process,
even if it's a couple of minutes, because when
you meditate, you know it, it takes about 20
minutes and a session of meditation and you
will get mainly a couple of minutes out of it.
00:07:56:10 - 00:08:14:04
Speaker 2
You know, where you really in this
process we talk about mindfulness,
but basically where your mind lasts in a way
really in your heart center. And this is a
reset button. So this is just basically everybody
understands when you work out and you are sore,
you take a massage or whatever you
do. And this similar is for our brain.
00:08:14:04 - 00:08:41:24
Speaker 2
So this is basically the physical aspect
of meditation. And then obviously comes the
spiritual aspect. And you know, the connection
to God or the connection to the source. And
and as you just explained, you have a meditation
practice. And for me, the love to know was was
so profound when I experienced this frequency
that I said the concept of meditation sounds
for so many people, like, oh my God, that
sounds cool, but I never have time for it.
00:08:42:01 - 00:09:02:03
Speaker 2
When when we introduced the love tune, we
talked about chakra healing and I said,
listen, if we call it chakra, we lose 99% of
people because, yeah, everybody understands
the energy field. But chakra is something where
everybody goes, hey, listen, I'm stressed out,
you know I have no time for this. I prefer to
have a beer, you know, or a cocktail, whatever.
00:09:02:07 - 00:09:21:07
Speaker 2
That helps me to slow down, to unwind.
And this is why the love tune, I always
call it. Like it's kind of cheating it
because it's a shortcut to meditation.
And why is it a shortcut to meditation? And
this is why it makes it simple for people,
as we all know that breathe, that
brass can regulate our nervous system.
00:09:21:09 - 00:09:40:16
Speaker 2
So, you know, when you're fired up and you're
like breathing way too fast, you barely get any,
any oxygen in your brain, you're shallow
breather. And then you do this relaxing
brass work like inhale exhale, inhale exhale.
Similar to smoking a cigaret. Wait. You know,
this is why it's so relaxing for a lot
of people when they smoke cigarets.
00:09:40:16 - 00:10:03:18
Speaker 2
You know, besides the whatever the, the chemical,
bad effects of a cigaret or a vape, but they
actually inhale, exhale. It's good for us. You
know, this gives you the feeling of relaxation.
So this is why the love tunnel is basically a
shortcut to meditation. So it hammers exactly
into where all the doubters actually they're
where they go, like, man, I'm stressed out.
00:10:03:18 - 00:10:25:19
Speaker 2
No time for meditation, more work. I have no time
to go to work class or all this stuff. I have
no time for yoga. What is this woo woo for me?
Whatever people say. But this combines one thing.
So it really regulates your nervous system because
everybody can breathe. So you breathe through
this device and then the frequency vibrates
within your body and also outside of your body.
00:10:25:21 - 00:10:42:19
Speaker 2
And and this is what I wanted. I wanted to
have a device for someone that doesn't want
to read five books, that doesn't want to go to
a workshop, but still understands that maybe the
drink at night or the cigaret in the morning
is not the solution to have a balanced life.
00:10:42:21 - 00:10:59:15
Speaker 1
Yeah, yeah. Of course. Yeah, it's it's a it
sounds much more appealing to reach for the
love to in there than a cigaret. Right. Yeah.
I always, I always thought, I've never been
a cigaret smoker myself, but I always thought,
man, I wouldn't mind just a couple times a day,
have an excuse to go outside and get
in some fresh air with some people.
00:10:59:15 - 00:11:20:08
Speaker 1
That sounds pretty nice. Yeah. But, yeah. I
mean, so when it comes to when it comes to,
breathwork itself, I mean, I think there's
so much information about breathwork online,
I think a ton of people, I mean, there's so
many people that it has successfully helped.
But I kind of want to talk to the people who
have not really dove in into breathwork a ton.
00:11:20:08 - 00:11:34:07
Speaker 1
Like, maybe it's not really in their lexicon.
Maybe they still have in that category of like
spiritual kind of strangeness that they're maybe
not into. Because to me, I see that when we're
blowing into the Love Tuner, you've heard of
yoga nidra, right? Non. Sleep. Deep breath.
00:11:34:07 - 00:11:36:06
Speaker 2
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
00:11:36:08 - 00:11:51:21
Speaker 1
To me I think I've been correct me if I'm, if
I'm perceiving this incorrectly Sigmar. But,
when you're blowing into the love tuner,
it's almost doing that thing in yoga nidra
where you kind of pretend you're blowing
through a straw, like through pursed lips,
and it kind of forces you to breathe out a
lot slower than you would have originally.
00:11:51:21 - 00:12:11:23
Speaker 1
And for some people, I mean, it might have been
weeks, if not months, since they've even breathe
out like that. You know, like the other ways
that we do it is, you know, we grab a beer,
we have a cigaret, we overeat, we, you know,
we're humans. This is how we've, like, learned our
coping mechanisms to lower our heart rate and make
our breath, you know, our rates per minute slower.
00:12:12:00 - 00:12:26:11
Speaker 1
So can you bridge that gap a little bit for
me, I guess? I know I kind of said a lot there,
but I think about, like, non sleep,
deep breaths, yoga nidra blowing out,
slowly and kind of like, as if it's through
a straw. How is that sort of thing helpful?
00:12:26:13 - 00:12:58:23
Speaker 2
Yeah. I mean, every time when you regulate
your exhale or like breathing through
a straw or whatever, just like, there's
so many press when I'm at box breathing,
there's 100 thousands of different modalities
out there. But the most important thing
is to slow down the exhale. And with the
loved, you know, what actually happens is,
I, I know that soon, maybe not picking it up,
but when I inhale exhale through this tuna,
it makes this sound and by creating the
sound, it gives me a feedback on my exhale.
00:12:59:00 - 00:13:19:04
Speaker 2
So when you just blow through a straw,
for example, or you do regular press work,
you don't really know how good your breath
swig is. This device gives you a feedback.
It goes right away. When the tone drops or
changes frequency, then you know you need to
inhale again. Fill up your lungs and exhale. So
I don't know if you picked it up, but I'm trying.
00:13:19:06 - 00:13:41:14
Speaker 2
He I don't know if you could hear it sometimes
soon filters it out. So but basically it gives
you an audible feedback. And that makes
it easy because breaths work you you need
to learn how to do correct press work. So
it is is nothing that you pick up and go
like I watch a YouTube video for two minutes
and now I'm perfect in my press work calls.
00:13:41:16 - 00:14:01:09
Speaker 2
Also, when you do the, the yoga practice. So
you need to learn it, you need to go somewhere,
with the tuna. It basically does it
right. You need to read the leaflet
and you got it. You have right away this
press work exercise that is just to the
point. And then you get better
and better. You exhale extends.
00:14:01:09 - 00:14:23:11
Speaker 2
You create a a strong a long volume. You improve
your immune system. But the understanding of
brass work is the most important thing for
a lot of people to even understand why,
to slow down the brass. So as we talked earlier,
people understand when they whatever have a
cigaret and whatnot. But the deep brass
is like, I mean, I had a grandma grandma.
00:14:23:13 - 00:14:39:18
Speaker 2
She got like nearly 100 years old and the first
thing what she always told me when I was a child,
and it was like when I'm excited about something
and you could barely speak when you're five,
six years old, she always said to
me, take a brass, take a brass,
and she insisted on me like taking 2 or 3 brass.
00:14:39:20 - 00:15:01:07
Speaker 2
And then the communication was like, you know,
like normal, you know, like the excitement was
gone. The negative things happened most of
the time, probably. But, and this is what,
what people need to understand. So our nervous
system is on alert. So we are wired still,
like if we would be living in the caves and
on the high goes outside and we need to run.
00:15:01:07 - 00:15:23:02
Speaker 2
So we are consistently in this so-called fight
and flight mode. And this is still our wiring.
This is not you know, we don't need this in our
society anymore. And when you do a conscious
breathing break, what actually happens is you
get out of your fight and flight mode. So yeah,
the the parasympathetic nervous system
and the sympathetic nervous system,
this is what regulates our nervous system.
00:15:23:04 - 00:15:44:13
Speaker 2
And when you do a conscious breathing break
you get out of this pattern. So you escape
this fight and flight mode. And this calms your
nervous system. You make better decisions. And
it also brings in the so called here now. So this
is where actually meditation or any sort or any,
any heartfelt emotion can even
happen is by being in the here now.
00:15:44:15 - 00:16:10:16
Speaker 2
And the brass is basically your best friend.
You know, you come into this world and the
first thing you do is like, you inhale and
when you leave, you exhale. So and in between,
most people forget that this is our best
friend. So with breathing correctly,
you can heal a lot. You know not only your your
mental state, but you can also like physically,
like you know, if you breathe correctly,
you have a better immune system.
00:16:10:16 - 00:16:34:00
Speaker 2
You know, you have a lot larger lung volume
and you're just more capable during the day.
You know, like you, your heart is
not as struggling as if you don't,
you know, generate enough oxygen by breathing
correctly. So this is, for me, the most important
thing that people understand the power of press
work and then also the power of their own heart.
00:16:34:00 - 00:16:36:16
Speaker 2
So this is like the combination.
00:16:36:18 - 00:16:57:09
Speaker 1
Yeah. Wonderful. So what is the, there's a
there's a neuroscientist and a meditation teacher,
Sam Harris, if you ever heard of him. I
like that he he has kind of like a corner
of his speaking where he talks about,
meditation isn't necessarily like this.
Break glass in case of emergency.
In case of emergency situation.
00:16:57:09 - 00:17:15:07
Speaker 1
Like, it's not just, oh, you're feeling anxious,
you need to turn off all the sounds and get in
a quiet room and start meditating so you can,
you know, just get calm right away. You know,
he kind of explains that. Well. And, I
wonder where that sits for you as far as
the Love tuner goes, I mean, I'm sure it is
pretty helpful if you are in those moments.
00:17:15:07 - 00:17:29:08
Speaker 1
You're like, feel a little stress. I'm
suddenly noticing maybe I'm breathing
low and slow up in my chest.
I can have the love to inhale,
help me kind of relieve these things. But
outside of it being just like, you know,
I'm a little stressed. Let me, you know,
take a hit on my love to an a rather.
00:17:29:10 - 00:17:37:17
Speaker 1
How does it help by, you know, tuning in in
the morning when we wake up or before bed,
those sorts of things, like what are the
benefits outside of the emergency use?
00:17:37:19 - 00:17:57:13
Speaker 2
Yeah. So, I mean, you know, we all, I don't
know your generation when you grow up. But
back in the days when I grew up, we still had,
like, the radio alarm, you know, like the first,
the first song of the day, even if you liked
it or not, it was in your ear. So. And this
is basically when, when you use a lot of
tuner, you're setting the tone of the day.
00:17:57:15 - 00:18:22:06
Speaker 2
You know, you're you're exposing yourself. And as
was the last time you became your own instrument,
you actually become, vibrant. You know, you
vibrate on this frequency. That's the first
thing what I recommend people in the
morning to do. So it doesn't matter.
You don't even have to really get out of
bed. Just do this. One tune or two tunes,
whatever feels okay when you're in
this state of not being really awake.
00:18:22:07 - 00:18:44:13
Speaker 2
And this is very powerful because this
is literally setting the tone of the day,
everything what comes after just in a certain
practice. So I recommend people after they get
out of bed, whatever they do, if they go on a run
or if whatever their practice is, then take your
time and do a conscious tuning cycle. So and we
recommend like six cycles depending on the exhale.
00:18:44:13 - 00:19:11:20
Speaker 2
This can take up to like whatever 4 or 5
minutes. And you inhale you exhale. And
after this six cycles of breathing
and tuning through the love tuna,
you sit in silence for 30s. And this gives
you the real reset. This is basically your
morning routine if you want to call it like
you know, your morning spiritual hygiene,
your shortcut to meditation and and then when
you go to in the day this is comes more to this.
00:19:11:22 - 00:19:37:09
Speaker 2
You know what we talked earlier when it's in
an emergency and you go like, hey, listen,
I'm sitting in traffic and, and I'm late or
whatever I'm in front of and before a meeting,
I'm stressed out. I step outside at a
two mile quick. So this is this is like,
let's call it emergency tuning. And then
I really highly recommend people before
they go to bed because the the 520 it hertz
calms your entire system and it prepares you.
00:19:37:11 - 00:19:59:23
Speaker 2
So when you at the end of
the day, take again. Again,
I mean I always recommend six cycles
or more. I should not do last. If you
really do a tuning a tuning session. So you
should do your six cycles or whatever feels
good for you and then really tune the day
out. You know, also like have gratitude,
you know, for the day and prepare for the night
because we all go into state where we sleep.
00:19:59:23 - 00:20:18:14
Speaker 2
And this is like I mean, we all know
what's going on, but I, we sleep and,
and you can really tune yourself into it.
And a lot of people are suffering from,
you know, like, yeah, from not getting
enough sleep and, and especially our
society is so driven to this eight hours,
you know, I need my eight hours of sleep.
00:20:18:14 - 00:20:38:10
Speaker 2
But I don't say that this is not correct,
but it also helps you to relax and don't
panic if you wake up at night. Oh, it's like
it's something because it's it's. I heard
some time that the eight hours came out from a
mattress producer. And this is why they tell us,
you know, to sleep eight hours.
I don't know if this is true.
00:20:38:10 - 00:21:01:22
Speaker 2
I mean, I obviously try to get enough sleep
or enough sleep for me, that is healthy. But
I also don't panic when I wake up in the night
because, I'm in the most powerful poems. Most
powerful music was written in the night
hour. So there's some magic in the night,
too. And. And if you get this magic, you
can prepare yourself with the love tonight.
00:21:01:22 - 00:21:24:02
Speaker 2
So you. Most of the time, I tell people,
hey, listen, it gives you a better sleep.
You can sleep through it because your cortisol
level drops because of the 528Hz frequencies,
or this is I mean, you know it
for sure, but this is exactly,
the chemical that gets produced when
you're stressed out. So you're super tired,
you fall asleep, you sleep for two, three hours,
you wake up, boom, the cortisol levels too high.
00:21:24:07 - 00:21:44:20
Speaker 2
So the 528Hz helps you to regulate this. But
I even tell people, even if you wake up and
we all know this, like 4:00 in the morning,
2:00 in the morning, where we decide this is
the spiritual window. I said, if somebody wakes
up, I always tell people, use the tune and just,
you know, like lay there and just like, really
let the magic of the night happen, you know?
00:21:44:20 - 00:22:11:10
Speaker 2
And if you feel motivated and you're creative, get
up, write something. If you have a great business
idea, make some notes. And or if you have your
last one next to you, tell what is on your heart,
you know. So, so don't be so anxious about
oh my God. You know, I need to get up in
four hours and I'm losing my sleep because, you
know, we we can regulate ourselves, you know,
and it's more about to get rid of this fear
of this panic of, like, I need to sleep now.
00:22:11:10 - 00:22:31:24
Speaker 2
It's like, I get it. If you don't have
enough sufficient sleep and you have a
unhealthy lifestyle, that's always bad. But, was
was the tune I always tell people tune into sleep,
drift on your cortisol level. But
if you have this magic at night,
you know, tune a couple of times,
you know, and really enjoy it.
00:22:32:01 - 00:22:58:04
Speaker 1
Yeah, yeah, man, that sounds a lot better
than tuning into, you know, whatever. TikTok
or Instagram Reels history. Yeah. You know, yeah.
You know, I'm very human, too. I, I struggle with,
from time to time waking up. And the first
thing I do is go to my phone, you know,
and so I'm tuning into the frequency of whatever
the algorithm is want me to care about that day,
you know, and I think we can all
notice the difference when we do that
versus we wake up and we consciously
choose what we're going to consume.
00:22:58:04 - 00:23:04:06
Speaker 1
We start off on a good beat. So yeah,
love tuna in the morning and the middle of the
night. That sounds like a perfect tool then.
00:23:04:08 - 00:23:28:17
Speaker 2
Yeah. I mean, listen, I have it here to makes our
life easy. We all love it. We all are dependent
to it. But it takes a lot of discipline
not to because I'm running a company. So,
you know, like I always want to be
on top of. We work a lot with Europe,
so it's my time. So on early morning I
check my phone, I have to check my phone,
but I really try to at least the
first half an hour to an hour.
00:23:28:19 - 00:23:43:12
Speaker 2
There's nothing else besides, you know, my own
frequency and whatever rock somebody's boat,
you know, to go outside and take a deep
breath. Or I used to love tuna, but
don't get interfered in out by
by cellphones, computers, etc..
00:23:43:14 - 00:24:01:20
Speaker 1
Yeah, yeah, I have a my friend Spencer,
who's been on this podcast years ago.
He told me this thing that stuck with me and it's
really helpful, you know, like a lot of apps,
when you go to set your alarm for the morning,
it'll sometimes tell you how many hours you're
about to get if you wake up at a certain
time, which is, like, useful and not useful.
00:24:01:20 - 00:24:16:10
Speaker 1
But, regardless of what it says, I notice that
for a while I was like, oh yeah, I'm thinking
for hours is going to be going to
be a rough day, whatever, you know,
start telling yourself those stories.
But what he says, he says, regardless,
even if it's 30 minutes of sleep, he's about to
get whatever that number is, he tells himself.
00:24:16:10 - 00:24:33:02
Speaker 1
He says that's the exact amount that I
need for tomorrow. I'm going to be just
fine. And I started that kind of tricking
myself with that, too. And it's it's pretty
useful. So anybody listening who has that,
struggle of not getting their eight hours
and they make themselves stressed out,
you know, use a love tune in for sure,
but also tell yourself, whatever you
get, you're going to be all right.
00:24:33:04 - 00:24:34:23
Speaker 2
Exactly. Yeah. That's very important.
00:24:34:23 - 00:24:55:00
Speaker 1
Yeah, yeah. Man, I wanted to, I heard you say
a couple, like, just really cool facts about,
528. So I want to explore
a little more on the 528,
frequency just itself. I feel like nowadays,
even if people aren't super into spirituality,
even if they're maybe not musicians, they
probably have heard the five 28Hz thing.
00:24:55:00 - 00:25:16:23
Speaker 1
They probably, you know, on YouTube, you
can go, you know, 528 calm morning mood or
whatever it is. What is so not only what is
so fascinating and special about 528 but can
you also kind of demystify it a little bit?
So for people who, like I said, maybe that's
not normally their lexicon of communication. They
don't really use these frequency words very much.
00:25:17:00 - 00:25:21:01
Speaker 1
How can we explain it to them in a
way that kind of makes some sense?
00:25:21:03 - 00:25:46:21
Speaker 2
I mean, first of all, the 528Hz is not a man made
frequency. So it's a frequency. So first of all,
it belongs to the Society of Tones. And
the most powerful one is the 528Hz. And,
it occurs in every living matter. The humming
of the bees, in the chlorophyl of the leaves.
This is, for example, you know, every every
frequency has a color on the light spectrum.
00:25:46:23 - 00:26:12:22
Speaker 2
528Hz is green is also wise. It's the center,
the solar plexus heart center of our body. But
in in the leaves, when you measure leave,
it vibrates exactly, 528Hz and it's green
because of the light spectrum color green from
520 to. So this is just like a little bit of
a background where it's coming from. So it's
a cosmic divine frequency was never manmade.
00:26:12:24 - 00:26:44:02
Speaker 2
The second thing is it was never mystified. It was
actually occurring in our music at scale. So the
original musical scale, the regular scene out was
528Hz, and the quick, whirring choir for example,
600 of the Choir of Christ have
been chanting on this frequency
and have been healing entire communities
in in the churches back then in Europe,
the same thing was the organ itself in
the church was calibrated correctly.
00:26:44:02 - 00:27:11:10
Speaker 2
So when they hit the C note, it, it
actually produced 520. It hurts. So
it connected communities and and yeah,
through history it got interfered with
this frequency. And at one point we ended up
with a new musical frequency and not frequency.
It was a new musical scale where the eight tone
got manipulated and went from 444Hz to a 440.
00:27:11:12 - 00:27:38:16
Speaker 2
And what it did is it made the C
note disappear because everything
is regulated out of the atom. And so 528Hz
disappeared in our musical scale. And this
is like when now people talk about 528
oh, it's there's such a mystic about it,
you know, what is what is this, what
is the miracle tone and blah blah blah,
and and you, you listen to Professor Horowitz
and all his stuff, and, I mean, he's great.
00:27:38:16 - 00:28:11:14
Speaker 2
He brought the 528, movement back in the 80s. And
I really recommend everyone that is listening.
Check him out. He tells you very profound
stuff. A lot of stuff might sound conspiracy,
but it's not. It's literally what happened. And
there's a reason why we are not in harmony. And
by being dissonance, even with the music that
we are listening to and super interesting, John
Lennon composed imagine that is the most known
love and peace song since over 50 years in 528Hz.
00:28:11:14 - 00:28:28:20
Speaker 2
So he knew about it. And this is why when
people talk, what is it? Is is woowoo is
this kind of weird? Is this kind of new age?
No, it's super old. It was always around and
this is how it actually should be. So we
are just bringing back a forgotten tone.
00:28:28:22 - 00:28:46:22
Speaker 1
Yeah man. Well so well said I love that. I feel
like you broke that down so well man. Yeah. Okay
so maybe we will dip our toes in the conspiracy
side of things for just a few minutes at least.
Why would we? I feel like I've read some things
online. Why would we go away from from 528?
00:28:46:22 - 00:28:55:03
Speaker 1
Like what? What are the kind of the
conspiracies there? Or what are the,
you know, assessments in the zeitgeist?
Rather like, what do people say?
00:28:55:05 - 00:29:16:05
Speaker 2
I mean, if you look at how
divided humanity is right now,
I mean, we we go back in history and we
don't know everything about history. That's
true or not. But all cultures have been
dealing with sound, you know, all the way
to Nicholas Tesla. He built the frequency
healing machine over 100 years ago. Yeah.
00:29:16:05 - 00:29:44:02
Speaker 2
You find on and off somewhere a doctor or,
house petitioner that that uses frequency
healing machines. They're all out there.
But the mainstream is not frequency. The
mainstream is pills and whatnot. You
know, all this stuff has frequencies,
but they're not beneficial frequencies. So
when we talk about. But conspiracy is like,
if you have people in harmony,
why would they start a war?
00:29:44:02 - 00:30:09:14
Speaker 2
You know, why? Why would they care?
Oh, man. If you're in harmony and
you're happy with your family and you know
there's abundance of money there, you know,
we all are healthy. We we never had so much
wealth around the world that we have right
now. I know we are so well taken care of
and but we are so divided, you know, and,
and and this balance is, I think this answers
the question of that we are not unified.
00:30:09:16 - 00:30:36:09
Speaker 2
And you can only separate people by
manipulating whatever they're exposed
to. And everything has a frequency. And for
me, when I when I started digging into this,
I said like, wow, what people that are part of
who put so much effort into interfering with a
frequency that there must be something,
you know, and then on the other hand,
we have so many frequencies out there
that we unknowingly are not good for us.
00:30:36:09 - 00:30:53:19
Speaker 2
You know, they are influencing us. So we
are exposing ourselves all day long to
negative frequencies. And we are just
like it is imbalance state. You know,
like when you play a guitar, when
you play a piano, as soon as you
hear that the tone is off, you retune it.
We as a human, we run around like crazy.
00:30:53:19 - 00:31:13:21
Speaker 2
You know, we're totally out of tune and we take
no time to retune. And yeah, at 500 planet hertz,
we align with this frequency. It's
it's a great human retune. You know,
you can retune. You can back, you get back into
balance. And in this state of mind, you know,
you just make better decisions
and you can access your heart.
00:31:14:01 - 00:31:43:18
Speaker 2
And this is what I think, talking about,
conspiracy. I mean, we can go into name
like 10,000, you know, accidents or incidents
in history where somebody interfered with
something. But the overall understanding is
it's the separation of humanity, and, and,
and this is not my take on, on on conspiracy.
This is what you see daily and all like,
I mean, we turn on the TV and you go like,
whoa, you know, like, by the way, talking.
00:31:43:18 - 00:32:07:04
Speaker 2
That's a bad frequency. If if you expose
you yourself to this kind of news,
it's not healthy that I know. And and this
is like, it's it's a, it's a manipulation
and some people call it the matrix,
but, humanity can only escape out of
this conspiracy or whatever you want to call
it, by literally tuning in to what is human.
00:32:07:04 - 00:32:28:18
Speaker 2
You know, what is human? The biggest power we
have is, is the connection to the divine and
the connection to our heart, to this is
literally the cycle. And I think if, if,
if you for yourself understand how to access this,
you just have a better life quality. And I mean,
I always refer to Carl Jung. He said, if you
look on the outside, you become a dreamer.
00:32:28:24 - 00:32:45:10
Speaker 2
If you go inside, you awaken. And that's
basically what it is. So if you're in harmony,
you awaken. If you are in dissonance.
Yeah, that takes a little longer. And,
you need to work very hard on it. And so
I think it's all about unifying humanity.
00:32:45:12 - 00:33:11:10
Speaker 1
Yeah, absolutely. I mean, I, you know, my
background for many years I have, like 14,
15 years as a DJ and, I have definitely, you
know, so if I'm going through my playlist of my,
my list of songs, one of the, columns is the key
in the keys in my program. In the DJ program,
they're actually colored and, you know, like,
you're, you know, you can kind of relate them.
00:33:11:10 - 00:33:25:05
Speaker 1
If you're looking at the chakra system, you know,
say break it down to seven simple colors
that you can kind of equate, like your red
ones are going to go to your root chakra or
your orange ones next, you know, like these
different songs. They have kind of a different
feeling to them when you play them, you know.
00:33:25:05 - 00:33:45:12
Speaker 1
And so I can as a DJ, I can build kind of a
journey up to where, you know, if I started with
a heart center song, it might not really resonate.
But if I build up from the bottom or even build up
until down, by the time I play, you know, 30,
40 minutes in, by the time I play that Heart
Center song, it's a whole different experience
in the room or in the, event that I'm playing.
00:33:45:12 - 00:34:05:05
Speaker 1
So, I, I've seen it. I've seen it firsthand, you
know, as I get a little bit better at mixing in
key and, like, trying to see what happens really
in front of me, you know, I've had some pretty
profound experiences by intentionally, like using
my colors, seeing where we're at with our chakras,
kind of tuning into what I'm feeling from
the the crowd in the audience in that moment.
00:34:05:05 - 00:34:25:24
Speaker 1
And, you know, in some ways they kind of
select the songs in a weird way. It's it's
it's a cool thing. But, yeah, I mean, I
imagine the same thing can be said about,
you know, churches or kirtan or any sort
of group coherence experience. I mean,
you mentioned Carl Jung. He, he studies
the collective unconscious a lot.
00:34:26:01 - 00:34:41:20
Speaker 1
Do you think that by you tuning in to 528 in
the morning, do you think that has a positive
effect as you go about the world, like as you
interact with people, your energy being centered,
does that have like a ripple effect with the
people that you interact with? Would you say.
00:34:41:22 - 00:34:58:14
Speaker 2
I, I think so, I think so, like I mean
it's like but it's the same thing. Like
I wouldn't want to call the the love tumor
like the peacemaker. And you walk around into
two and everybody smiles and, you know,
just walk through a street and smile at
someone you know. So if your vibration
is up, people will react it for sure.
00:34:58:14 - 00:35:20:06
Speaker 2
You always have people that are just so
close down. But in general, you know,
like when you see a friendly face on
a street, you know, it's kind of like,
you know, you react to it in a positive way. And
the same thing is when you, you know, like raise
your frequency you or tune your frequency in the
morning and it's for sure recognizable by people.
00:35:20:06 - 00:35:43:07
Speaker 2
And even if they don't get it consciously,
but if you get it subconsciously,
so you're just in a better tuned state
of mind. And we all know when we go
into a room and sometimes we have this
feeling as a this kind of off, you know,
it's kind of weird vibe. Or you have whatever, you
meet random people and you have a conversation and
you walk away from it and you go like, oh,
you know, that's this was very uplifting.
00:35:43:07 - 00:36:08:23
Speaker 2
So that's all frequencies. So
we all vibrate. And I think,
the most important thing is like, as
we are so run by our brains is that we
have also this kind of solid hygiene, you
know, like, no negative talk, you know, no
self-criticism. You know, you can be you can be,
you know, ever try to improve yourself, but you
need to be really careful how you do it, you know,
and then also always being grateful for stuff.
00:36:08:23 - 00:36:26:03
Speaker 2
I mean, gratitude is is a big one. And when it
comes to tuning, like if you tune in the morning,
yes, it helps, but you need to be
also really aware of, you know,
it's not like, oh, I tuned in. Everything
is okay. It takes way more. You know,
first of all, you need to
be authentic to yourself.
00:36:26:03 - 00:36:48:19
Speaker 2
So this is where everything starts because
we always talk about love can heal the world.
And love is the most powerful frequency in
the universe. But authenticity, you know,
lays the ground. You know, authenticity is
actually the key to wholeness. So because if
you're not offended, you know, you you can
tune whatever you want or tune, you know,
because the frequency is just not in resonance.
00:36:48:21 - 00:37:16:21
Speaker 2
So it's very important to scrape away all the
stuff. And everybody has it and everybody has
to do their work. And then you can start building
up similar what you just explained as a teacher.
And I really appreciate this a lot because I
was very into electronic music. I still am,
and I, I saw the whole movement through the
90s and, EP's and whatnot, and I have seen
this tribal effects, what music can happen
and when a teacher knows how to build it up.
00:37:16:23 - 00:37:47:06
Speaker 2
And this is why dancing is so important, because
it goes to the entire chakra system. And this is
why I always tell people, listen, just dance,
you know, just have your chocolate flow, happy
energies flow and and open up to the, to the song,
you know, like literally. And there's so much what
the teachers can do, you know, like literally
starting, as you said, with the root chakra all
the way up that you feel like kind of, you know,
like light minded or enlightened, whatever you
want to call it, you know, because it touches
your heart and then it opens up to the divine.
00:37:47:08 - 00:38:07:15
Speaker 2
And if this is done correctly, this is why
I'm promoting with so many teachers around
the world. I'm talking to them. I said, listen,
guys, I understand that it's a big it's a big
moneymaker. It's it's a big entertainment
saying. But we humans, we always danced
together. You know, dancing unites. You
know, it's it's such a cool thing to do.
00:38:07:17 - 00:38:30:06
Speaker 2
And and it doesn't matter, you know, like,
yes, drugs play an effect in this whole night
nightlife, but that's totally fine, you know,
like, this was always done in, in, in a way or
another. But the most important thing is if those
people would play the real harmonic music, you
know, where the key, where the C really hits the
heart, you know, that would be like so uplifting.
00:38:30:06 - 00:38:52:22
Speaker 2
And it there's you barely hear a difference,
you know. But it's cool. And I see now is
more and more teachers are doing it and
I know there's big labels behind it is
big companies behind it that are not in favor
of this. But, I mean, as you said, you know,
like you can really guide. And then at one
point, the DJ actually follows the tribe,
if you want to call it, you know,
and and this is this unifying moment.
00:38:53:02 - 00:39:05:17
Speaker 2
And I think people that dance together, you know,
it's like it's it's the most profound thing
you can do. It's it's beautiful. It's like
going to a church and just, you
connect directly to the source.
00:39:05:19 - 00:39:28:10
Speaker 1
Yeah. I mean, I think of the, you know, how
many years of human experience were we just,
you know, we didn't have electricity
for example. And so night comes around,
we have the fire and let's start playing
some drums and dancing around like you know,
the the amount of culture that was probably, you
know, almost invented during dancing ceremonies.
00:39:28:10 - 00:39:48:16
Speaker 1
I mean, I just feel like it's such a part of who
we are. I mean, especially when we do, you know,
we now have all this important research and
we have science and we can start to, like,
connect a lot of these dots that, you know,
we could kind of prove, hey, this is like you
mentioned, for example, bees, you mentioned
that bees, they're buzzing is it's five 28Hz.
00:39:48:18 - 00:40:05:17
Speaker 1
I mean, that's something that until we had the,
the, the proper tools to measure that we
wouldn't know that sort of thing. And yeah.
So it just makes sense that it's it brings us
back to our center, brings us back to to our,
you know, our fullness, our, our most authentic
self, as you said, it makes total sense.
00:40:05:19 - 00:40:13:18
Speaker 1
One question I did want to ask for you. If
someone's listening right now and they've never
heard of the Schumann resonance, the Schumann
frequency, how would you describe that to them?
00:40:13:20 - 00:40:36:01
Speaker 2
I mean, we we talk about the, you know, the
frequency of mother mothers of our planet
and, and, it's very interesting because it was
pretty steady for a long, long time. And then
the last 15 years, I don't know if you have
seen this research is the planet actually is
raising its own frequency. And, you need to dig
pretty deep to, to find all this information.
00:40:36:03 - 00:41:03:10
Speaker 2
But, the Schumann resonance is so
important for us to understand that
our own planet has a frequency.
So we have a frequency. And this,
this understanding of of energy, of
everything is basically, you know,
vibration. It's it's and frequency. This is the
most important thing. And businesswoman frequency,
it's it's funny that you mention it because
it's raising its own frequency right now.
00:41:03:12 - 00:41:27:12
Speaker 2
And this in the last 15 years. Tremendously.
So what does this mean? Planet is telling us
basically guys, get up and raise
your frequency. And this is also
why we see so much craziness in the world right
now. Because the way our society is built is not
high vibrational. We have very low vibrational,
you know, we we lost connection to to nature.
00:41:27:14 - 00:41:48:21
Speaker 2
We we are destroying our own planet. And I mean,
and, I don't want to sound too hippie ask here,
but if you cannot embrace nature, I mean,
this is God's temple, you know, like,
and and there's not one. Being in this
world destroys. It's its own, you know,
a planet, you know, like, I mean, we
are doing it, and that's the craziness.
00:41:48:23 - 00:42:11:24
Speaker 2
So with the human frequency, it is so interesting
because it's raising the frequency right now and
we we are not doing it. So and this is why
it's harder on us, you know, it is why so
many people are like literally, disconnected but
not disconnected from each other, but literally
disconnected from the universe, you know, where
they don't feel, they don't feel to belong anyway.
00:42:11:24 - 00:42:40:12
Speaker 2
Like they doubt everything. You know, they're
doubting the divine. They're doubting, you know,
the the cycle of life. They're doubting nature
because it it's really stressful on them because
the planet is basically telling us, raise your
frequency. The planet Mother Earth is doing it.
And we need to really follow. And I mean, this
is the best sign, in the universe right now
that it's time for humanity to raise frequency
and not doing the opposite to lower frequency.
00:42:40:14 - 00:43:02:05
Speaker 1
Yeah, yeah. You know, it's very interesting
that, you would think our species would have
some sort of important part of our culture
that everyone just agrees upon, like, hey,
you know, all eight plus billion of us make sure
that this is important. We all focus on like,
what is humanity and what are we doing? And like,
what are we going towards and what's the
point of all this and that sort of thing?
00:43:02:05 - 00:43:21:10
Speaker 1
I know it gets lost in religions
and those arguments start happening,
but I think even before you get to religions,
even before you get to any of like the
exact terminology, it's pretty obvious,
like what we're trying to do. Like if we look at
I always like the example of like, say you're an
alien and you're looking down at the earth and
you're like, what are those crazy apes doing?
00:43:21:11 - 00:43:48:16
Speaker 1
You know, like, what are they doing down
there? I feel like we could probably have
a pretty short conversation and
we could all agree upon. Yeah,
we're kind of just doing this, you
know, we're inventing these things,
and we're we're developing families and we're
loving each other and we're growing and, you know,
growing towards some direction. And I don't know,
I just think it seems pretty obvious when we're,
you know, growing away from that or, you
know, going the wrong way or, you know,
going against the frequency of what we should be
of the direction we should be going in, you know?
00:43:48:18 - 00:44:07:16
Speaker 1
So, yeah, it's just very cool that more and
more people, you know, are waking up. You know,
that's such a broad term in so many ways. But,
I mean, you said, was it last 15 years or so,
the human frequency was. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
I think in the last 15 years there's been
a lot of people have had some form of
spiritual awakening, that's for sure.
00:44:07:18 - 00:44:25:17
Speaker 2
Absolutely. I mean, you know, this is when and
when we all talk about, you know, 2020 and Bentham
and whatnot, but I think so on. And so it's a good
side effect. You know, a lot of people woke up. I
mean, a lot of people are like in a deep state of
sleep right now and, and, totally disconnected.
00:44:25:19 - 00:44:49:11
Speaker 2
But yeah, they came so many people out
and go like, listen, that that cannot
be. And I think it's, it's beautiful
to see this, you know, because in 2019,
we have been doing a bunch of seminars in
Europe with Love Tuna. And everybody was like,
hey, this is where we are going to. And
then boom comes this, this one year and,
and and it brought a lot of people
back to like giving up completely.
00:44:49:11 - 00:45:11:17
Speaker 2
So then they never ever went back to the
spiritual paths. And so like, okay. So anyway,
everything is, is. Yes. And but they are
not a people. They really are awakened,
you know. And the thing is, I don't believe that
the collective awakens, you know what I mean? I
believe it takes the individual and it takes
one individual, you know, to uplift others.
00:45:11:19 - 00:45:36:16
Speaker 2
So and that's what it is. And then it comes to,
you know, what? You decide on what I
said earlier. Now, if you go inward,
you awaken or you look on the outside, you become
a dreamer. So I think it becomes down to to the
individual and obviously then it will impact the
collective. And, and I think it's it's a very,
very exciting times that we are living in, you
know, and, and everything is possible right now.
00:45:36:18 - 00:45:55:00
Speaker 1
Yeah. Amen to that man I, I totally
agree. Man okay. We're getting up
here in time. I kind of want to end this with,
I think what you've said so far, but I really like
what you said about authenticity. Can I ask you,
and, you know, if there's, of course, no wrong
answer to this, can I ask you say something.
00:45:55:02 - 00:46:17:17
Speaker 1
Listen to this right now. And they're on
some sort of awakening journey. They're
on some sort of. Maybe they're just beginning.
Maybe they've been doing it for ten years and
they just like this kind of stuff. Whatever.
They're in some sort of awakening experience.
What message could you give them or
something to be to carry with them?
How do they remain authentic
and listen to their intuition?
00:46:17:19 - 00:46:43:14
Speaker 2
I think it's, you know, when a lot
of people talk about that channeling,
you know, so people have channels. But
at the end of the day, everybody is a
channel. And so channeling is just it has
form of intuition. And if you don't have
the right feeling about something
then that's the answer. You know,
I mean this is literally like really trusting
in yourself and it's all about self-empowerment.
00:46:43:14 - 00:47:06:15
Speaker 2
And this is what what I'm writing in my book
about it, what I tell people how to use the
love to know how to practice it. It's basically
like really trust in yourself because it's about
your intuition and nobody can take this away
from you. This is your channel to the divine,
and it's your intuition. If
something doesn't feel right,
then there's something you know and
you don't have to find an explanation.
00:47:06:15 - 00:47:31:10
Speaker 2
And yeah, maybe the guy had a bad
day or whatever. My job doesn't mean
this or there's so no, no, you have
this intuition and you by yourself,
you need to be as self empowered to really
trust yourself, to trust your intuition.
So and I know, especially when you go on this, on
this path and it's like sometimes it's a little
bit unfair because the people that awaken
the old girl at one time, they get lonely.
00:47:31:10 - 00:47:51:24
Speaker 2
At first they get super happy, then they get
lonely. Sort of went to all these phases,
but at the end of the day, it's literally
like tuning into your own intuition,
like becoming this channel, you know, because
you are living your life. Nobody else is living
your life. You make your decision and
they should be based on your intuition.
00:47:52:01 - 00:48:11:01
Speaker 1
Well powerfully said I really love that. I mean
and it to me I'm just thinking it's not an arrival
either. It's like a constant. We've got to have
our daily habits almost, you know things like the
love tune or things like meditation, things like
breathwork, you know, having a habitual day that,
you know, equates to you being able to
tune in to your intuition, you know.
00:48:11:04 - 00:48:11:11
Speaker 1
Yeah.
00:48:11:11 - 00:48:28:20
Speaker 2
So and and I mean, and tuning into,
into intuition is like, you know,
spirituality sometimes sounds so serious,
but I always tell people, just keep it light,
you know, like, really, you know, state of
cool as they stay funny as they stay happy,
you know, don't take it too
serious for this. We have religion.
00:48:28:22 - 00:48:44:15
Speaker 1
Yeah. Amen. Amen. Yeah. Oh, man. Keeping it light.
All right. Oh, Sigmar, thank you so much for this,
man. I feel like you're such a wealth of
information. I really enjoyed getting to
not only learn about, you know, your products
and your journey, but getting to talk to you
and and being able to ask you all these
questions to your face is truly a gift.
00:48:44:15 - 00:48:49:00
Speaker 1
So, one more time, man, thank you so much
for for spending this time with me, buddy.
00:48:49:02 - 00:48:51:04
Speaker 2
Awesome. Thank you so much for having me.
00:48:51:09 - 00:49:06:15
Speaker 1
Yeah, yeah. So anybody listening,
check out down below. You'll see
the description. You can check out
some more of Sigmar. Check out his
YouTube you guys website down below.
Check out Love Tune and of course,
anything else that may not be down there
that you want to send people towards. Sigmar.
00:49:06:17 - 00:49:28:07
Speaker 2
Yeah. Like, check out my book. It's called One
Journey. It's, published by Waterside. I have
a copy here. This is how it looks like. It's
available on Amazon. And it's a quick read. And
it's covers everything that we talked about when
it comes to frequency brushwork and also like,
you know, some spiritual guidelines
that might be helpful for people.
00:49:28:09 - 00:49:31:12
Speaker 1
Right. And then did you say you're
right in a second one right now?
00:49:31:14 - 00:49:32:21
Speaker 2
No. This is my only one.
00:49:32:22 - 00:49:46:05
Speaker 1
Okay. That one's already out. Okay. So it's
already out. They can get it now. Cool. Yeah. All
right, brother, I'm going to end this recording.
Everybody listening? Have a great day. Stretch,
drink some water and check out love to learn more
of Sigma's work. We'll see you next time. I'm
just going to end the recording here.